Andrew B. Thompson

722 League St • Philadelphia, PA 19147

Phone: 508-333-7265 ● E-Mail: thompsona1@gmail.com ● Twitter/Github: @andrewbt

Who am I? Civic technologist with passions for journalism, geospatial web software, open source, and open data, experienced in the art of listening to and engaging with technical and non-technical communities.

Education

Haverford College, Haverford, PA

Bachelor of Arts, May 2012

Major: Growth and Structure of Cities

Minor: Computer Science

Selected coursework: Urban Culture and Society, Mass Media & the City, Urban Politics, History of Modern Architecture, Data Structures, Programming Languages, Compiler Design, Theory of Computation

Senior Thesis: Programming Politics: Building an Open Government through Free and Open Source Software

Universitat Pompeu Fabra, Barcelona, Spain

Spring 2011

Coursework in Spanish language, journalism, and urban design.

Relevant Experience

Azavea Inc., Philadelphia, PA

May 2011 - Present

Community Evangelist

(May 2012 – Present)

- Organized 2013 Global Mainstage event of NASA's International Space Apps Challenge hackathon.
 Coordinated with NASA senior staff and astronaut, solicited corporate sponsors, arranged venue, promotion, and challenge and program development. One Philadelphia team, ISS Base Station, went on to international recognition as the Best Use of Hardware.
- Organized Hacks for Democracy elections and politics themed hackathon, fall 2012. Pioneered the "finishathon" concept of hosting subsequent events and a second round of judging weeks after initial hackathon weekend since adopted by other events. Also participated as a member of StateRep.Me team; helped team stick together and continue iterating Django app months into 2013. Team has participated together in other hackathons since.
- Mentor/Speaker, participant, and sponsor at a dozen other hackathons and major civic tech events, including TechCamp: Philadelphia, TransparencyCamp 2013, Random Hacks of Kindness, etc.
- Staff exhibits at several open source, technology, and urban and community forestry conferences.
- Answer community questions on mailing lists and IRC, provide customer support, and write technical documentation, sample code, and blog posts for Azavea's open source civic software and API products: OpenTreeMap, DistrictBuilder, Open-Data-Catalog, GeoTrellis, and the Cicero API.

Marketing Intern

(May 2011 – May 2012)

• Conducted sales lead research and outreach; wrote copy for case studies, blogs, and product collateral; coordinate mass mail and e-mail campaigns.

Axeda Corporation, Foxboro, MA

Summer 2009 / Summer 2010

Software Testing Intern

- Performed QA testing on SaaS enterprise software for remote monitoring / Internet of Things
- Tested and installed new builds, proofread documentation, reported bugs
- Researched Section 508 compliance and performed usability testing within the product

Other Experience

Haverford College, Haverford, PA

Jan 2009 – May 2012

Editor, News and Web - The Bi-College News

- Reported, wrote, and edited articles for weekly student newspaper serving two campuses.
- Managed team of reporters and fielded criticism from readers.
- Accomplished two major website migrations using both Wordpress and Joomla CMS's, while preserving 10 year historical article database. Provided training on new site to entire Editorial Board, copy editors, photographers, and writers.

Student Writer, College Communications Department

Sept 2009 - Dec 2010

- Wrote, edited, and researched articles and photography for College website and alumni magazine.
- Digital Asset Management; Photoshop; InDesign

The Woonsocket Call, Woonsocket, RI

Summer 2009

Intern Reporter

- Reported and wrote articles on local news and events for daily newspaper in Rhode Island (~10,000 circulation)
- Learned paper layout skills using QuarkExpress.

Sears, Woonsocket, RI

Feb 2008 - Aug 2008

Appliance Salesperson

• Commission-based sales and customer service of kitchen, laundry, and floor care appliances.

Town of Hopedale, Hopedale, MA

Sept 2007 - May 2008

Website Content Management Intern (High School)

• Met with and identified needs and desires of town department managers, and translated into content for www.hopedale-ma.gov, some of which is still in use today.

Skills and Talents

- **Programming Languages, in order of fluency:** Python, JavaScript (some jQuery), Scheme (LISP dialect), PHP, C++, Java
- **Geospatial and GIS specific:** CartoDB, Leaflet, Google Maps, GeoServer, Quantum GIS, Esri ArcGIS and ArcGIS Online/Server, PostGIS, CartoCSS
- **Software and SaaS:** Salesforce.com; GitHub; FogBugz; Wordpress, Joomla, Concrete5, and other CMS administration; Microsoft Office / LibreOffice; Paint.NET
- Other Technologies and Tools
 - o **Web:** HTML/CSS, HTTP, ReST APIs, Django, Apache, nginx; Mac OS X and Linux server administration
 - o Data: JSON, XML, CSVs, OpenRefine, PostgreSQL/PostGIS, MySQL
 - Other: Git, Sublime Text 2/Vim/Emacs, Bash, Vagrant, Agile/Scrum development
- Experience in long-term, non-proft strategic planning for 501c3 Philadelphia Yearly Meeting (Quaker/Religious Society of Friends)
- Fluent in Spanish (non-native speaker)
- FCC Licensed Amateur Radio Operator (KB1NXJ)